<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../../articleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<newspaperArticle>
    <meta>
        <publisher>The Behrend Beacon</publisher>
        <issueDate>2003-04-18</issueDate>
        <issuePage>3</issuePage>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <header>
            <title>Behrend dedicated as arboretum</title> by<author>Katie Zellars</author> staff
            writer </header>
        <p n="1">The Behrend campus will officially be dedicated as an arboretum, a place where
            trees are grown for scientific and educational purposes, and a member of the
                <org>American Association of Botanical Gardens and Arboreta</org>. The ceremony will
            be on Wednesday at 10:15 a.m. in the Glenhill Circle. in conjunction with Earth Day
            activities.</p>
        <p n="2">"It formalizes and recognizes a lot of the good things we've done already," said
                <person>Dr. Thomas Wortman</person>, special projects assistant to the dean and head
            of the <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org>. "It also gives us some pretty dramatic
            opportunities for education and research."</p>
        <p n="3">The campus prides itself that at least one state tree from every state is located
            on its 725 acres.</p>
        <p n="4"><person>Dr. Jack Burke</person> and the <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org> will
            host the ceremony. Speakers will include <person>Wortman</person>; <person>Dr. Zachary
                Irwin</person>, associate professor of political science and <org>Landscape
                Committee</org> member; and <person>Donna Mindek</person>, Harborcreek Supervisor
            and member of the township's <org>Bicentennial Committee</org>.</p>
        <p n="5">Community members and Klein Elementary third graders, who will participate in
            activities before the ceremony, will attend the dedication. Refreshments will be served
            afterwards and tree guides will be given.</p>
        <p n="6">Students and professors think the campus becoming an arboretum is a great thing and
            agree that the campus is really a beautiful one. Sophomore Mindy Schwartz thinks that
            the arboretum will be great for education.</p>
        <p n="7">"It gives you a chance to learn about trees that are in your own backyard," said
            Schwartz.</p>
        <p n="8">"I think it's really good that we're doing it," said ecology professor Pamela
            Silver. "A lot of people have worked really long and hard to achieve that status."</p>
        <p n="9">The goal of establishing the campus as a national arboretum has been going on for
            only a year but the college has been dedicated to preserving and expanding its natural
            library for years.</p>
        <p n="10">Even before <person>Mary Behrend</person> donated the original 400 acres to Penn
            State, the Behrends added East Asian and other exotic trees into the native
            landscape.</p>
        <p n="11"><person>Wortman</person> says at least 300 species and subspecies of trees are on
            campus. It would be nearly impossible to categorize all the different kinds of trees
            with all the hybrids that have developed but it is one of their goals, which will be
            included into class curriculum.</p>
        <p n="12">Other goals for the arboretum include research and grant funding. It will also
            highly involve the community.</p>
        <p n="13">"We are part of a group of education institutions around us and we live in a
            region, state, country, and a world that we cannot ignore," says
                <person>Wortman</person>. "An arboretum is part of that thinking."</p>
    </body>
</newspaperArticle>
