<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../articleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<newspaperArticle>
    <meta>
        <publisher>The Behrend Beacon</publisher>
        <issueDate>2002-10-11</issueDate>
        <issuePage>1</issuePage>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <header><title titleId="2002-10-11">Greener Behrend Task Force tackles campus ecological issues</title> 
                <author>Erin McCarty</author></header>
        <p n= "1">On Monday, Bruno's unveiled the Ecomug, a reusable mug emblazoned with a reminder to
            reduce, reuse, and recycle. Students can buy the mug, full of coffee or pop, for a
            dollar and refill it for 80 cents. It comes with a hook allowing it to be attached to
            bookbags, making it easy to transport.</p>
        <p n= "2">Bruno's disposes an estimated 10,000 cups a week, so the mugs have the potential to
            greatly reduce waste on campus. Nonetheless, it was one of the smaller projects
            undertaken by the <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org>, which focuses on campus
            sustainability issues.</p>
        <p n= "3">"It's the message that's so important," said <person>Dr. Thomas Wortman</person>, chair
            of the task force. "A project like this will create some commitment."</p>
        <p n= "4"><person>Wortman</person> is also pleased that the project was a collaborative effort
            between the <org>task force</org> and <org>Housing and Food Services</org>. Students in
            Jeanette Schnars' environmental science class conceived the idea. The cups were designed
            specifically for Behrend, but they are expected to spread throughout the rest of the
            Penn State system.</p>
        <p n= "5">Since it formed last year, the <org>task force</org> has developed more than 20 projects
            designed for Behrend's ecological benefit. Right now, it is focusing on two major
            projects. First, it is writing a grant with <org>Erie County Recycling</org> to get
            money for a composting machine. This machine would be the first of its kind in Erie
            County, and the resulting compost would be used as fertilizer in various areas around
            campus.</p>
        <p n= "6">Second, it is working to inventory what trees are on campus; decide where trees should be
            planted; re-beautify the entrance area; develop a map of trees on campus; and have
            Behrend declared an arboretum. At least one specimen of each of the 50 state trees
            resides at Behrend.</p>
        <p n= "7">"There is a major push for all things trees." said <person>Wortman</person>. "This is
            exactly the time for us to celebrate the arboreal heritage of the campus."</p>
        <p n= "8">As the <org>task force</org> tackles major issues, students can display their ecological
            awareness in a variety of simple ways. For instance, they can take advantage of the new
            printing system in Behrend's computer centers that prints on both sides of the paper and
            make efforts not to print unnecessary items.</p>
        <p n= "9"> The <org>task force</org> identifies seven major sections within the sustainahility
            issue: reducing energy use: conserving water: minimizing waste: increasing the
            healthfulness of food and reducing its waste; protecting and preserving natural areas;
            using environmentally friendly practices; and promoting ecological stewardship within
            the community.</p>
        <p n= "10">"It's important to do the little things. - said <person>Wortman</person>. "Anything we do
            locally has a direct impact on everything_ outside hcie It's not wally about a greener
            Behrend: it ., about a greener everything."</p>
        <p n= "11"><person>Wortman</person> went on to say that we, the beneficiaries of the Behrend
            family's generosity, have an obligation to the gift they gave us. He feels that they
            would he proud of the steps that are being taken to preserve the natural beauty of the
            campus.</p>
        <p n= "12">"Ecology is not a political issue," said <person>Wortman</person>. "It's for everybody."
            The <org>task force</org> is seeking more participants, especially students. For more
            information, please refer to the website www.greencampus.psu.edu</p>
    </body>
</newspaperArticle>
