<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../articleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<newspaperArticle>
    <meta>
        <publisher>The Behrend Beacon</publisher>
        <issueDate>2003-02-28</issueDate>
        <issuePage>1</issuePage>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <header>
            <title titleId="2003-02-28">Behrend Declared Arboretum</title>
            <author>Jen Henderson</author>
        </header>
        <p n="1"><org>The Greener Behrend Task Force</org> has
            great ideas on keeping the campus
            environmentally preserved. This group
            of people, alongwith many others, has
            helped to further develop Behrend
            environmentally. These changes have
            led the campus to be offered
            membership in the <org>American
            Association of Botanical Gardens and
            Arboreta</org>.</p>
        <p n="2">The campus is now known as an
            arboretum and will be fully inducted in
            a ceremony that will take place on April
            23</p>
        <p n="3">Throughout the campus's 725 acres
            there are a variety of diverse trees in
            remote locations and in various buildings. The Behrend campus has at least
            one of each of the 50 states' trees.
            Pennsylvania's tree, the eastern hemlock, are located all over, including the
            other side of the Studio Theatre. The
            state tree ofHawaii is located inside the
            Kochel Building, in an attempt to keep
            it alive and healthy</p>
        <p n="4">While most trees are located throughout our campus, some are inside, and
            others grow in the green house which
            is located behind the <person>Otto Behrend</person>
            building.</p>
        <p n="5">Dr. Thomas Wortman, special
            projects assistant to the provost and
            dean, along with Dr. Robert Light, associate provost and dean, lead the task
            force at Behrend. <person>Wortman</person> is very
            proud of what has been done with the
            surroundings thus far and believes the
            original owners would be too.</p>
        <p n="6">He is especially proud of "how we
            maintain the beauty and integrity of
            this setting and how we've acted responsibly towards the Behrends' gift
            to us. Frankly I think the Behrend
            family would be pretty proud of what
            we have done here, they would he
            happythat we are conserving the sort
            ofthings that they gave us fifty five
            years ago."</p>
        <p n="7"><person>Sam Marvit</person> is a freshman student who is 
            also actively involved with the task force.</p>
        <p n="8">"It gives students a chance to he involved simply with consen ation because it is a crisis today in America,
            mainly because we use most of the
            world's resources," said <person>Mary</person> it
            "Hopefully we can take one step at
            making it less of a crisis and working
            with nature as opposed towards working against nature, 
            which is most often happening."</p>
        <p n="9">Marvit has done this work before
            and believes that this is a wonderful
            chance for students to get invoked.
            "It's great for students because it also
            prepares them for what the world may be like in future 
            times once conservation grows more rapidly, as it is now.
            I've been involved with a lot of conservation groups, outdoor
            groups, environmentalist groups, and thought that this would 
            just be one more to help."</p>
        <p n="10">The Behrend campus being named an arboretum benefits 
            everyone involved.  "It gives us the opportunity to have an 
            organized effort toward using this natural environment here,
            specifically our trees and our other botanical resources."
            said <person>Wortman.</person> "It also is a reach out to the
            community so our students can then
            interact with the other people and the
            things around them."</p>
        <p n="11">Earth Day is April 22 and the task
            force along with student activities and
            organizations are working towards setting up a day of events to celebrate.
            There will be educational activities on
            sustainability issues and open stage
            performances. Area school children
            will be invited to take tours ofthe campus to see why it has been chosen to be
            called an arboretum. The final details
            for this event will be available within
            the next few weeks</p>
        <p n="12">Last year, Eco-mugs were introduced
            and this year will be no exception.
            Housing and Food services will bring
            the mugs back, but redesigned to keep
            the idea fresh. This program seemed
            to be very successful last year.</p>
        <p n="13">On April 23, a ceremony will be held
            inducting the Behrend campus as an arboretum. There are three arboretums in
            <org>Erie County: the Erie Zoological Society</org> and the <org>Lake Erie Arboretum and
            Frontier Park</org>, along with the Behrend
            campus. Behrend's arboretum is very
            large and spread out over heavily
            wooded areas in the gorge, managed areas, wild areas, such as on top ofthe
            ski hill, meadow, and grassland.</p>
        <p n="14">Three hundred various species have
            been identified thus far and experts are
            still performing research on this
            project. It can prove to be difficult due
            to the time and knowledge needed to
            work on this process. The group is also
            looking to make a pamphlet showing
            where the various trees are located
            throughout the campus.</p>
        <p n="15">Other members of the task force involved in these projects include: Dr.
            <person>Edwin C. Masteller</person>, <person>R. Thomas Guth</person>,
            landscape supervisor, <person>Dr. Zachary
            Irwin</person>, associate professor of political
            science, <person>Dr. Paul Barney</person>, lecturer in biology, <person>Dr. Roger Knacke</person>, director of
            the School of Science, <person>Dr. Michael
            Campbell</person>, associate professor of biology, along with Wortman and Light.
            Many of the original ideas for these
            projects originated from <person>Masteller</person>, who
            is now retired.</p>
        <p n="16">The Task Force is focusing on
            sustainability. This entails living
            within means and using the resources
            that Earth provides. The Task Force's
            seven main issues include: reducing energy use, conserving water, minimizing waste, increasing the healthiness of
            food and reducing its waste, protecting and preserving natural areas, using
            "green" practices, and promoting ecological stewardship within the community.</p>
        <p n="17">The mission of the arboretum is to
            conserve and promote the legacy ofthe
            campus' unique natural botanical resources through: advancement of related education, outreach, research, and
            conservation efforts; documentation
            and enhancement of the campus' botanical diversity; and the maintenance
            of the campus' inspirational woodland setting. Their vision
            is that it will be recognized as an important education, outreach
            research, and conservation resource.
        </p>
        <p n="18">When asked if he is looking for others to aid in this project, <person>Marvit</person> said,
            "I've used publicity towards conservation, but I believe that we shouldn't try
            to recruit people, we aren't an army.
            At the same time people should want
            to work with us, we are only improving the area and where students live and
            study.</p>
        <p n="19">"We are trying to keep up with national
            standards of conservation and a lot of
            other universities are probably a lot better than we are, as good as it seems.
            But what we are doing isn't novel at
            all, it is like everyone else. It's in no
            way radical. It's just about conservation."</p>
        <p n="20">In response Wortman said, "The
            ideas are hardly radical, it's very mainstream. It's about conservingthe beauty
            and the biodiversity, it's not about making political statements.</p>
        <p n="21">"Arboretum is certainly a work in
            progress, it's not somethingthat comes
            in a box and you open it up and then
            you have arboretum. Arboretum requires the efforts of a whole lot of
            people and it changes, sometimes day
            to day. It's a dynamic thing, rather than
            a static one."</p>
        <p n="22">Everyone
            on the Behrend campus should be
            proud of what the Greener Behrend
            Task Force has done for the campus.
            "If we believe so strongly in our trees
            to become an arboretum, then students
            are probably the most critical part of
            that," said Wortman.</p>
    </body>
</newspaperArticle>
