<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../articleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<newspaperArticle>
    <meta>
        <publisher>The Behrend Beacon</publisher>
        <issueDate>2007-03-30</issueDate>
        <issuePage>2</issuePage>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <header>
            <title titleId="2007-03-30">Task force works towards a greener Behrend</title><author>Jessica Samol</author>
           
        </header>
        <p n="1">Penn State Behrend's campus is ecologically committed to protecting and conserving the environment. In 2001, <org>The Greener Behrend Task Force</org> formed to
            address sustainability issues on campus. The purpose of the <org>Greener Behrend
            Task Force</org> is to promote a campus community at Behrend that is educated and
            involved in maintaining a responsible relationship with the natural resources of
            the earth.</p>
        
        <p n="2">Members of the <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org> are committed to building respect
            for the environment and are developing and implementing strategies for campus
            practice and policies. In addition, the task force is addressing seven main issues
            at Behrend, which include reducing energy use and promoting cleaner fuels, using
            water in a conservative and respectable manner, minimizing solid and liquid
            waste, increasing the healthfulness of food and reducing its waste, protecting natural areas, incorporating "green" practices into the construction and renovation of
            facilities, and promoting ecological stewardship within the college community.</p>
        
        <p n="3">The Greener Behrend Task Force is making great efforttoward creating a more
            environmentally friendly and sustainable environment. In 2003, the creation of
            the <org>Arboretum at Behrend</org> brought a much greener scene to the campus. More
            than 200 species oftrees are represented in the Arboretum, making it a haven by 
            local environmentalists for its interesting trees. Senior Associate <person>Dean, Dr. Robert
            Light</person> said, "The faculty and staff have further developedthe Arboretum at Penn State
            Behrend which works with the ground crew to make the campus a place recognized
            for its education, research, and outreach related to its trees and plantings." In addition, <person>Light</person> said, "The faculty and staff have established a Landscape Committee that
            works with the grounds crew to beautify specific sites on campus".</p>
        
        <p n="4">The task force has also been successful in incorporating the use of geothermal
            heating in residence halls and reclaiming heat from the Junker Center pool area to use
            in other parts of the building. In addition, automatic heating and cooling setbacks are
            being utilized when buildings are not in use, and automatic light shutoff has been
            installed in classrooms and parking lots when they are not in use. Among other
            promising efforts to reduce energy use, <person>Light</person> said, "They are working with housing
            to promote the installation of"low-flow" showerheads in residence halls, and working 
            with housekeeping to maintain the college's activerecycling program."</p>
        
        <p n="5">Educating the Behrend community about sustainability is a vital asset to create a
            more knowledgeable and environmentally friendly campus. "We need the faculty,
            staff, and students to realize how important becoming sustainable is, not only on
            campus, but in general. The entire community must drive sustainability efforts and
            not wait or rely on a few to push the program," <person>Light</person> said.</p>
        
        <p n="6"><org>The Greener Behrend Task Force</org> is integrating sustainability topics into the curricular offerings throughout the college as part of their education campaign. The
            community can become more involved in creating a more sustainable environment
            by "Learningmore about sustainable issues and working with college leaders to promote environmentally friendly ideas," <person>Light</person> said. With future plans for the task
            force, Behrend will continue to stand as a role model for other institutions by promoting a greener environment.</p>
    </body>
</newspaperArticle>
