<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="../articleSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<newspaperArticle>
    <meta>
        <publisher>The Behrend Becacon</publisher>
        <issueDate>2004-01-03</issueDate>
        <issuePage>2</issuePage>
    </meta>
    <body>
        <header>
            <title>Greener Behrend Task Force preaches sustainability</title> By<author>Annie
                Sevin</author>staff writer</header>
        <p n="1">The <org>Greener Behrend Task Force </org>is fo cusing on educating students and
            the community about sustainability this year. Sustainability, according to a
                <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org> pamphlet, is “about living within our means,
            working with the Earth and respect.” <person>Dr. Thomas Wortman</person>, assistant for
            academic admin istration heads the Task Force and <person>Mary Beth Peterson</person>,
            director of the Career Development Center, is also a committee member for the
                <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org>.</p>
        <p n="2"> “About three years ago the University asked us [Penn State Behrend] to include
            something into our planning process about ecological sustainability, instead.. .we
            decided to do.. .a major ef fort towards sustainability and that is [where] the
                <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org> started,” said <person>Wortman</person>.</p>
        <p n="3">The <org>Task Force</org> has seven goals. One: to reduce energy use; two: conserve
            wa ter; three: minimize solid and liquid waste; four: increase the quality of food and
            reduce its waste; five: protect and preserve natural areas; six: use “green” practices
            into the construction and reno vation of facilities; and seven: promote ecological
            stewardship within the col lege community.</p>
        <p n="4">According to <person>Wortman</person>, “We’re con centrating our energy this year
            on edu cation by what we call stewardship, which is getting the word out to the whole
            campus community about how important sustainability is.” <person>Ms. Peterson</person>
            is in charge of the edu cation goal. <person>Peterson</person> says that, this year, the
                <org>Task Force</org> is concentrating on educating why sustainability is in
            everyone’s best interest and why people should take part in it.</p>
        <p n="5">So far, the <org>education committee</org> held an energy conservation workshop for
            faculty and staff about winterizing their homes. <person>Peterson</person> said that a
            good way of promoting conservation of energy use and minimizing waste on campus is to
            have people start in their homes. For the students whose homes are on campus, the
            committee wants to work with RA’s and through clubs and organizations to begin
            brainstorming about reducing en ergy usage on campus, recycling and conserving water
            (reporting leaks, tak ing shorter showers, etc.).</p>
        <p n="6">The <org>committee</org> is planning some events for this year, but nothing
            specific has been finalized yet. They are, how ever, talking about using the “Stall
            Stories” flyers to help educate students and faculty about water conservation, and
            possibly about having a “Greener Behrend garage sale” at the end of the spring semester.
            The sale would be an alternative for students who want to throw out useless items at the
            end of the year - instead of just pitching them into the dumpsters, they can donate them
            to the sale. All the proceeds they would make would then be turned back into the efforts
            towards the <org>Greener Behrend Educational Committee</org>.</p>
        <p n="7">“Our biggest struggle...is trying to fig ure out what is the balance between
            progress and preservation,” said <person>Dr. Wortman</person>. He says sustainability is
            im portant because “this College believes in Friday, December 3, 2004 maintaining the
            history of this property. This was a wonderful gift from the Behrend family and we have
            a responsi bility to maintain the integrity of this beautiful piece of natural
            space.”</p>
        <p n="8">Last year, the <org>Task Force</org> concentrated their efforts on The Arboretum at
            Penn State Behrend, which is the largest uni versity arboretum in the region. Accord ing
            to a media publication by the <org>Greener Behrend Task Force</org>, “An arboretum is a
            collection of woody plants that are labeled, cataloged and mapped... Through the local
            contributions of local garden clubs and <person>Dr. Edwin C. Masteller</person>, the
            college has been able to add to the pre existing collection of the Behrends. These
            collections, the gorge areas and all of campus (totaling over 725 acres) is what is
            included in the Arboretum at Penn State Behrend...”</p>
        <p n="9">“I think sustainability is a goal for everyone,” stated <person>Dr.
                Wortman</person>. The <org>Task Force</org> is encouraging student in volvement.</p>
        <p n="10">“We would love some high energy stu dents who have real concerns for these sorts
            of topics to join our group and add to our energies,” says <person>Peterson</person>.
                <person>Dr. Wortman</person> said, “We have zero students directly involved with any
            of our committees right now, it has been a struggle to get students involved...but I’m
            certain there are students that would be willing to help out at least by giving us their
            opinions or by getting involved in some planning...”</p>
        <p n="11">If any students are interested, they may contact <person>Ms. Peterson</person> at
            the <org>Career Development Center</org> (x 6164) or by e-mail: mbpl@psu.edu.</p>
    </body>
</newspaperArticle>
